Guide to the Edward Lee Plumb Papers, 1856-1912
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE 1871. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 13. 1871, June 22.Grace S. Bristed to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1871, June 23.R.S. Chew to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1871, June 23.A.E. Douglass to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1871, June 24.A.E. Douglass to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1871, July 1.Wm. F. Roelofson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1871, July 6.Elijah Ward to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1871, July 13.R.C. McCormick to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1871, July 20.R.C. McCormick to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 21. 1871, Aug 10.N. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1871, Aug 13.A.L. Lee to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. [1871], Aug 22.,Dionisio Lopez Roberts to Feliciano Herreros de Tejada. Introducing E.L. Plumb., Copy L. in Spanish
  - 24. 1871, Sept 3.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1871, Sept 4.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., A.L. in Spanish.
  - 26. 1871, Sept 9.E.L. Plumb to C.K. Garrison. Report to Mexico of International RR Co. of Texas., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1871, Sept 9.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1871, Sept 9.E.L. Plumb to Wm. Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1871, Sept 21.Ignacio Mejia to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 30. 1871, Sept 22.Jose del Castillo Velarea to E.L. Plumb., A.L. In Spanish.
  - 31. 1871, Sept 22.S.Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 32. 1871, Sept 24.William Whiting to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1871, Sept 25.William Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1871, Sept 26.W. Newbold to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1871, Sept 29.E.L. Plumb. to Horace porter. Re-election of Juarez., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1871, Oct 5.Matias Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1871, Oct 6.E.L. Plumb to William W. Belknap., A.L.S.
  - 38. 1871, Oct 13.Wm. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1871, Oct 23.John Black to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1871, Oct 25.D. Fergusson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1871, Oct 30.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall. Mexican situation, mention Porfirio Diaz., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1871, Oct 31.W.H. Hurlbert to E.L. Plumb., Tel. in Spanish.
  - 43. 1871, Nov 2.Jas. Sullivan to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 44. 1871, Nov 5.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. Cuban affairs, Spanish-U.S. relations., A.L.S.
  - 45. 1871, Nov 6.Wm. W. Belknap to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 46. 1871, Nov 18.E.L. Plumb to O.E. Babcock. Porfirio Diaz & party, military preparations, manifesto of military dictatorship., A.L.S.
  - 47. 1871, Nov 20.E.L. Plumb to Gabriel Mancera., A.L.
  - 48. 1871, Nov 21.Gabriel Mancera to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 49. 1871, Nov 21.E.L. Plumb to Gabriel Mancera., A.L.S.
  - 50. 1871, Nov 23.Feliciano Herreros de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish.
  - 51. 1871, Nov 28.Andres Leguizamo to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. Form Ltr. S. in Spanish.
  - 52. 1871, Nov 29.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 53. 1871, Dec 4.E.L. Plumb to O.E. Babcock., A.L.S.
  - 54. 1871, Dec 7.Wm. H. Hurlbert to E.L. Plumb., Tel. in Spanish.
  - 55. 1871, Dec 7.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 56. 1871, Dec 7.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 57. 1871, Dec 9.Manuel de Zamacona to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 58. 1871, Dec 16.Manuel Payne to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 59. 1871, Dec 18.E.L. Plumb to Manuel Payne., A.L.S.
  - 60. 1871, Dec 21.E.K. Nelson to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 61. 1871, Dec 22.Tiburcio Monteil to E.L. Plumb., N.S. in Sp.
  - 62. 1871, Dec 26.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall. Cuban affairs, slavery, Whitelaw Reid., A.L. S.
  - 63. 1871, Dec 27.Wm. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 64. 1871, Dec 28.E.L. Plumb to O.P. Morton. International RR, Mexico, Cuba., A.L.S.
  - 65. 1871, Dec 28.E.L. Plumb to Chas. A. Whitney & Co. Re-establish Steamer line between New Orleans and Vera Cruz., A.L.S.
  - 66. [1871?]W.F. [Buckley]to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1872, January-April (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1. 1872, Jan 1.Y.R. Cardena y Cia, to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. D.S. in Sp.
  - 2. 1872, Jan 1.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1872, Jan 3.E.L. Plumb to Andres Leguizano., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1872, Jan 5.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1872, Jan 5.Mrs. Taylor to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 6. 1872, Jan 9.E.L. Plumb to O.P. Morton. Surrender of Oaxaca and flight of Diaz., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1872, Jan 11.Wm. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1872, Jan 11.Gabriel Mancero to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 9. 1872, Jan 12.Manuel de Pino to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. D.S. in Sp.
  - 10. 1872, Jan 15.Ignacio M. Altamirano to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. D.S. in Sp.
  - 11. 1872, Jan 18.T. del Valle to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 12. 1872, Jan 22.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb, Cuban affairs and policy., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1872, Jan 22.E. L. Plumb to Ignacio M. Altamirano., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1872, Jan 26.Estamslao Canedo to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 15. 1872, Jan 29.Matias Romero to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 16. 1872, Jan 29.E. L. Plumb to GeorgeE. Church., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1872, Jan. 30.E. L. Plumb to William Pitt Kellogg., A.L. S.
  - 18. 1872, Feb 5.E. L. Plumb to R. C. Mc-Cormick. Railroads., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1872, Feb 19.Julie F. Uhink to E. L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 20. 1872, Feb 20.Thos. F. Read for W. H. [Mills] to E. L. Plumb. Railroad tariff, etc., L.S.
  - 21. 1872, Feb 29.Mr. and Mrs. G. B. Crawley to E. L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 22. 1872, Mar 1.George E. Church to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1872, Mar 20.Matias Romero to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 24. 1872, Mar 5.Wm. Hunter to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1872, Mar 8.Ignacio M. Altamirano to E. L. Plumb., Ptd. N. in Sp.
  - 26. 1872, Mar 14.J. M. Mata to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 27. 1872, Mar 14.E. L. Plumb to Wm..Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1872, Mar 14.E. L. Plumb to Charles Sumner., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1872, Mar 17.C. A. Bristed to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1872, Mar 18.E. L. Plumb to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1872, Mar 18.E. L. Plumb to Albert H. Plumb. Protestant Riley., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1872, Mar 27.E. L. Plumb to Wm. Henry Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1872, Mar 30.Wm. Henry Hurlbert to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1872, Mar 30.E. L. Plumb to George E. Church, (A.L.S.)
  - 35. 1872, Apr 2.Matias Romero to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1872, Apr 8.Estamslao Canedo to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1872, Apr 9.P. Santacilia to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 38. 1872, Apr 12.Wm. Hunter to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1872, Apr 16.Emilio Velasco to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 40. 1872, Apr 27.E. L. Plumb to Caleb Cushing., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1872, Apr 29.George E. Church to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1872, Apr 30.E. L. Plumb to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 43. 1872, Apr.Copia para el Sor Ministro da Hacienda de las Bases presentadas informalmente al Ministro de Fomento de las Republica de Mexico por Don Eduardo Lee Plumb en representacion de laCompania del Ferrocarril ynternacional de Texas, para la construccion de un ferrocarril desde el Rio Bravo del Norte hasta la Ciudad de Mexico y hasta el Oceano Pacifico, en continuacion del ferrocarril que la referida Compania esta construyondo actualments al Araves del Estado de Taxas., A.D. in Sp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1872, May-August (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1. 1872, May 1.Carlos Lenox Kennedy to E. L. Plumb., Ptd. form ltr. S. in Sp.
  - 2. 1872, May 1.E. L. Plumb to Matias Romero., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1872, May 2.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 4. 1872, May 2.H. C. Riley to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1872, May 3.E. L. Plumb to Gabriel Mancera., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1872, May 4.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 7. 1872, May 9.[Enzenberg] to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 8. 1872, May 12.M. de Zamacona to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 9. 1872, May 16.Estamslao Canedo to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1872, May 16.Ignacio Mejia to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 11. 1872, May 22.Wm. J. Palmer to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 12. 1872, May 22.E. L. Plumb to Wm. J. Palmer., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1872, May 31.Wm. Hunter to E. L.Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1872, June 5.L. Mariscal to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 15. 1872, June 5.[Franeise?]-illegible., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 16. 1872, June 8.C. Robbos to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 17. 1872, June 9.T. Guzman to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1872, June 11.George E. Church to E. L. Plumb. Bolivian enterprises., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1872, June 23.Matias Romero to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 20. 1872, June 26.E. L. Plumb to Horace Porter. Grant-Greeley., A.N.S.
  - 21. 1872, June 28.E. L. Plumb to William Hunter. Maxican congress, execution of Cuban Jose Quclan., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1872, July 1.[Simon Stevens] to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1872, July 8.R. G. Guzman to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 24. 1872, July 12.Jose M. Baranda to E. L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 25. 1872, July 15.E. L. Plumb to William H. Hurlbert. Railroad business, Grant., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1872, July 16.E. L. Plumb to Horace Porter., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1872, July 17.E. L. Plumb to George E. Church. International RR Co., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1872, July 24.Wm. H. Hurlbert to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1872, July 24.E. L. Plumb to Benito Zomin Ferias. Death of Juarez, Lerdo president., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1872, July 30.E. L. Plumb to Wm. H. Hurlbert. Lerdo becomes president., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1872, July 30.E. L. Plumb to Horace Porter. Events following death of Juarez., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1872, Aug 7.Henry C. Hall to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1872, Aug 14.E. L. Plumb to Charlie [Plumb]. Railroad., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1872, Aug 23.E. L. Plumb to Wm. Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1872, Aug 24.E. L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall.Railroad., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1872, Aug 30.E. L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. Mexican affairs, political and economic., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1872, September-December (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1. 1872, Sept 5.E. L. Plumb to David A. Wells., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1872, Sept 24.F. de Gavay to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 3. 1872, Sept 25.Wm. Hunter to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1872, Oct 2.Luis Gutierrez to E. L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 5. 1872, Oct 10.David A. Wells to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1872, Oct 14.E. L. Plumb to Thomas H. Nelson., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1872, Oct 14.M.de Zamacona to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 8. 1872, Oct 21.Henry C. Hall to E. L. Plumb. Death of Seward., A.L.S.
  - 9. [1872, Oct]E. J. Perry to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 10. 1872, Nov 1.R. Cardena & Col to E. L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 11. 1872, Nov 5.E. L. Plumb to Charles A. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1872, Nov 7.N. Davila to E. L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 13. 1872, Nov 7.J. T. Tronbridge to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1872, Nov 8.Henry C. Hall to E. L. Plumb. Re-election of Grant., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1872, Nov 8.A. Lancaster Jones to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 16. 1872, Nov 19.Matias Romero to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 17. 1872, Nov 23.George Jones to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 18. 1872, Nov 25.Jose M. Iglesias to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 19. 1872, Dec 3.E. L. Plumb to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1872, Dec 3.E. L. Plumb to David A. Wells., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1872, Dec 6.Samuel C. Reed to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1872, Dec 9.Charles [White?] to E. L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 23. 1872, Dec 13.Mr. and Mrs. George B. Crawley. to E. L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 24. 1872, Dec 18.W. T. Sherman to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1872, Dec 24.E. L. Plumb to Mexican Ry. Co., A.N.
  - 26. 1872, Dec 26.Ygnacio M. Altamirano to E. L. Plumb., N.S. in Sp.
  - 27. 1872, Dec 27.Thomas Grandison to E. L. Plumb. Inauguration of Vera Cruz RR., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1872, Dec 28.H. G. Marguand to E. L.Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1872, Dec 28.E. L. Plumb to Thomas Grandison., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1873, January-June (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1. 1873, Jan 13.Pedro [Princon] to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 2. 1873, Jan 14.Abner Doubleday to E.L. Plumb. Texas-Mexico border trouble, General Cortina., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1873, Jan 15.George B. Crawley to E.L. Plumb., N. in Sp.
  - 4. 1873, Jan 17.Albert [Binstodd?] to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 5. 1873, Jan 17.[I] Mariscal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1873, Jan 22.Manuel C. Portugal to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 7. 1873, Jan 28.David Hoadley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1873, Jan 28.Lancastrian Co. of Mexico to [E.L. Plumb]., Ptd. L.
  - 9. 1873, Feb 5.Lancastrian Co. to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 10. 1873, Feb 20.Guillermo Pritchard to E.L. Plumb., N.S.
  - 11. 1873, Feb 21.Ramon G. Guzman to E.L. Plumb., N.S. in Sp.
  - 12. 1873, Feb 21.E.L. Plumb to Henry G. Marguand., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1873, Feb 26.[F.W. Worrall] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1873,John H. Wyman to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 15. 1873, Feb 28.M. [Arpiroz] to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 16. 1873, Mar 6.Ignacio Mejia to E.L. Plumb., N.S. in Sp.
  - 17. 1873, Mar 7.Mariano B. Soto to E.L. Plumb. Assoc. de Ingenieros Civiles y Arguitectos, A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 18. 1873, Mar 12.E.L. Plumb to David Hoadley., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1873, Mar 31.E.L. Plumb to Horace Porter., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1873, Mar.G.H.F. to unknown. Mexican population, freight movement, etc., L. extract
  - 21. 1873, Apr 11.Mariano Escobedo to E.L. Plumb., N.S. in Sp.
  - 22. 1873, Apr 12.E.L. Plumb to Henry D. Cooke., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1873, Apr 12.[A.C. Tornetz] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1873, Apr 15.Wm. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1873, Apr 18.Jose de Mihalovitsy to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 26. 1873, May 2.Manuel de Zamacona to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 27. 1873, May 16.E.L. Plumb to William Hunter., A.N.S.
  - 28. 1873, May 17.Alice G. de Yturbide to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1873, May 20.Jose M. Iglesias to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 30. 1873, May 23.Edward M. McCooke to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1873, May 29.Contrato celebrado entre el Ministerio de Fomento y el representante de la Compania del Ferrocarril Internacional de Texas s. Blas Balcarcel and E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 32. 1873, June 4.Walton W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1873, June 15.M.D. Markoe to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1873, June 17.Samuel C. Bigelow to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1873, June 17.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1873, June 19.E.L. Plumb to Charles P. Daly., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1873, June 20.Mr. Allsopp to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 38. 1873, June 24.Chas. X. Brown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1873, June 27.Count [Enzenberg] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1873, June 28.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1873, June 28.J.A. Skilton to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1873, July-October (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1. 1873, July 1.W. Newbold to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1873, July 7.Horace Porter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1873, July 17.John Hill to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1873, July 19.A.C. Diaz to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1873, July 21.L.A. Gobright to unknown., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1873, July 22.Lizzie C. Marsh to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1873, July 27.E. L. Plumb to Lizzie C. Marsh., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1873, July 28.Walton W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1873, Aug 1.George Earl Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1873, Aug. 1.Hamilton Fish to E.L. Plumb.
  - 11. 1873, Aug 7.H.G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1873, Aug 11.J.D. Plumb to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 13-15. 1873, Aug 13.Galusha A. Grow to E.L. Plumb. International & Houston, and Gt. Northern RR Cosl., L.S. with copy and Spanish translation.
  - 16-17. 1873, Aug 14.Henry G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb. Cairo and Fulton RR Co. Copy certified Oct 15, 1873.
  - 18. 1873, Aug 14.H.G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb. St. Louis and Iron Mountain RR Co. Certified Oct 15, 1873., L.S. (certified copy).
  - 19. 1873, Aug 14.E.L. Plumb to W.W. Evans., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1873, Aug 15.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. Mexico, progress, RR contract., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1873, Aug 16.A. Brown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1873, Aug 19.E.L. Plumb to Henry G. Marquand. RR charter and contract., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1873, Aug 20.E.L. Plumb to Josie [D. Plumb]. Trip-N.Y. to Mexico City., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1873, Aug 23.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1873, Aug 28.E.L. Plumb to W.W. Belknap., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1873, Aug 28.E.L. Plumb to Walton W. Evans., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1873, Aug 28.E.L. Plumb to Henry G. Marquand., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1873, Aug 28.E.L. Plumb to Thos. W. Pearsall., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1873, Aug 28.E.L. Plumb to Nelson Spofford., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1873, Sept 3.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 31. 1873, Sept 12.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1873, Sept 12.[Archbishop of Mexico] to T.H. Nelson., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 33. 1873, Sept. 12.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 34. 1873, Sept 16.Estamslao Canedo to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 35. 1873, Sept 19.E.L. Plumb to Jose Maria Iglesias., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1873, Sept 20.Jose M. Iglesias to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 37. 1873, Sept 21.Alice G. de Iturbide to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 38. 1873, Sept 25.[Degallado] to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 39. 1873, Oct 1.Estamslao Caneda to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1873, Oct 3.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. N.Y. stock and money market, panic and failure., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1873, Oct 12.E.L. Plumb to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1873, Oct 13.E.L. Plumb to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 43. 1873, Oct 13.Simon Stevens to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 44. 1873, Oct 16.Conde de Enzenberg to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 45. 1873, Oct 16.Horace Porter to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 46. 1873, Oct 17.Ramon G. Guzman to E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 47. 1873, Oct 25.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 48. 1873, Oct 28.E.L. Plumb to D. Ignacie Mefia., A.L.S.
  - 49. 1873, Oct 29.R.G. Guzman to E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 50. 1873, Oct 31.E.L. Plumb to Ignacio Mariscal. Barron, Forbes & Co. and Almaden Quicksilver Mine., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1873, November-December (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1. 1873, Nov 4.Ramon G. Guzman to E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 2. 1873, Nov 5.E.L. Plumb to R.G. Guzman., A.D.S. in Sp.
  - 3. 1873, Nov 8.Simon Stevens to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 4. 1873, Nov 10.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. Cuban affairs, Virginius., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1873, Nov 12.Blas Balcarcel to E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 6-7. 1873, Nov 15.E.L. Plumb to [Balcarcel]., D.S. (draft and copy) in Sp.
  - 8. 1873, Nov 15.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1873, Nov 17.Unknown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 10. 1873, Nov 18.Henry G. Marguand to E.L. Plumb. Failure of Texas Pacific & Scott., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1873, Nov 18.E.L. Plumb to Jose Baranda., A.D.S.
  - 12. 1873, Nov 20.William Hunter to E.L. Plumb. Barron, Forbes & Co., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1873, Nov 20.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.N.S.
  - 14. 1873, Nov 22.E.L. Plumb to Wm. Henry Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1873, Nov 22.E.L. Plumb to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1873, Nov 23.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1873, Nov 25.Mr. and Mrs. Foster to legation of U. S., A.N.
  - 18. 1873, Nov 27.P. Santacilia to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 19. 1873, Nov 28.Walton W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1873, Nov 28.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1873, Nov 29.Wm. Cross-Buchanan to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1873, Dec 1.E.L. Plumb to Antonio C. Diaz., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1873, Dec 5.Segura to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. L.S. Luis G.
  - 24. 1873, Dec 6.[Blas Balcarcel] to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 25. 1873, Dec 6.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1873, Dec 10.Jose M. Iglesias to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 27. 1873, Dec 13.G Biagi to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 28. 1873, Dec 13.E.L. Plumb to Walton W. Evans. Mexican Co. contract and opposition and Vera Cruz., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1873, Dec 14.M.G. Granados to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 30. 1873, Dec 14.F. Perez Pruano to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Sp.
  - 31. 1873, Dec 24.Sociedad Mexicana de Geografia y Estadistica to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. invitation in Sp.
  - 32. 1873, Dec 26.G. Biagi. to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 33. 1873, Dec 31.F. Mefia., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 34. 1873, Dec 31.E.L. Plumb to Jose Raimirez., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 35. 1873, Dec 31.E.L. Plumb to Lucia Rodriguez., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 36-40. [1873?]Various lists of statistics.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1874, January - April (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1. 1874, Jan. 2.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1874, Jan. 8.Walton E. Evans to E.L. Plumb. South American railways - British and American., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1874, Jan. 10.Blas Balcarcal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 4. 1874, Jan. 13.Josefa Ocampo de Mata to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 5. 1874, Jan. 14.F. de Garay to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1874, Jan. 17.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1874, Jan. 20.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1874, Jan. 25.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1874, Feb. 4.Galusha A. Grow to [G. Coke?]., A.N.S.
  - 10. 1874, Mar. 13.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel. Trip by rail, Houston to N.Y., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1874, Mar. 13.E.L. Plumb to Estanislao Cañedo. re: death of Charles Sumner & Millard Fillmore., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1874, Mar. 13.E.L. Plumb to Sebastian Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1874, Mar. 14.F.F. Eltonwood to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1874, Mar. 24.T. [Beretasmontel?] to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 15. 1874, [Mar. 24].[L.] A. Brown to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 16. 1874, Mar. 26.Elizabeth L. Marquand to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 17. 1874, Mar. 27.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1874, Mar. 31.E.L. Plumb to P.H. Sheridan. Railroad business in Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 19. [1874, Mar.?].Wm. Henry Hurlbert to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. [1874, Mar.?].Wm. Henry Hurlbert to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1874, Apr. 4.[G.E. Feistun?] to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 22. 1874, Apr. 7.John L. Geiger to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1874, Apr. 11.Blawford Munroe to W. H. Hurlbert., copy A.L.S.
  - 24. 1874, Apr. 11.E. L. Plumb to Andrew J. White. murder of missionary Mr. Stephens., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1874, Apr. 19.John W. Foster to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1874, Apr. 21.H. Clarke (sec. Council of Foreign Bondholders) to E. L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 27. 1874, Apr. 21.E. L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A. L. S.
  - 28. 1874, Apr. 21.Andrew D. White to El L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 29. 1874, Apr. 22.E. L. Plumb to B. E. Babcock., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1874, Apr. 23.E. L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1874, Apr. 24.E. L. Plumb to John W. Foster, A.L.S.
  - 32. [1874, Apr. 27.]W. H. Hurlbert to E. L. Plumb, A.N.S.
  - 33. 1874, Apr. 28.E. L. Plumb to H. M. Hoxie re: Blawford Munroe., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1874, May - June (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1. 1874, May 7.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1874, May 8.Jose M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 3. 1874, May 11.Hyde Clarke to E.L. Plumb., N.S.
  - 4. 1874, May 11.Walter W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1874, May 11.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb. Mexican Co. dissolved., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1874, May 11.Luis Ramiro to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 7. 1874, May 12.N.M. Hoxie to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 8. 1874, May 12.F.D. Macin to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 9. 1874, May 12.Thos. M. Pearsall to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 10. 1874, May 14.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1874, May 14.E.L. Plumb to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1874, May 22.E.L. Plumb to W.W. Curtis, A.L.S.
  - 13. 1874, May 23.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1874, May 26.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1874, May 27.Walton W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1874, May 27.E.L. Plumb to H.M. Hoxie Railroad contract., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1874, May 31.Estanislao Cañeda to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 18. 1874, June 1.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1874, June 3.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1874, June 6.E.L. Plumb to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1874, June 10.Blas Balcarcel to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 22. 1874, June 10.E.L. Plumb to John L. Geiger., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1874, June 11.E.L. Plumb to Wm. H. Swift., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1874, June 19.E.L. Plumb to Samuel B. Ruggles., A.L.S. & copy of reply.